William Edgar Borah Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Office File, 1907-1940 (Box 1-528)
  - 1932-1933
    - State Department
    - Tariff
    - Taxation
    - Tracy, Thomas H., (2 folders)
    - Trust laws, repeal of (Box 373)
    - Unemployment
    - Veterans Administration
    - Veterans Bureau Hospital
    - War debt
    - Washburn, Robert M.
    - West Point, N.Y., United States Military Academy
    - World Court
  - 1933-1934 (Box 374)
    - Agricultural Adjustment Act
    - Agricultural Credit Corp.
    - Agricultural
    - Agriculture Department
    - Airmail contracts, cancellation of
    - Annapolis, Md. United States Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md.
    - Antitrust laws
    - Applications for loan, Public Works Administration
    - Applications for pardons (Box 375)
    - Applications for positions
      - A-S, (6 folders)
      - T-Y (Box 376)
      - Idaho boys
    - Appointments with Borah, (2 folders)
    - Appropriations
    - Arms munitions manufacturers, curtailment of
    - Articles, (2 folders)
    - Babb, James E.
    - Bank legislation (Box 377)
    - Banks, Wingfied, investigation
    - Biological survey
    - Bonus
    - Borah, William Edgar, personal
    - Business, miscellaneous
    - Central bank
    - Charity
    - Civil Service
    - Civil Works Administration
    - Civilian Conservation Corps
    - Claims
    - Coast Guard
    - Commerce Department
    - Commissioner of Reclamation, (1 folder) (Box 378)
    - Committee on Foreign Relations
    - Condolences
    - Congratulations
    - Congressional Library lists
    - Congressional Record
    - Corra Linn Dam
    - Cuba
    - Currency
    - Dictatorial powers
    - Documents, (2 folders) (Box 379)
    - Economic situation
    - Economy Act
    - Education legislation
    - Exchange, regulation of
    - Farm Credit Act
    - Farm Credit Administration
    - Federal buildings
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration, (2 folders)
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration, investigation (Box 380)
    - Federal Farm Loan
    - Federal Home Loan Bank Board
    - Federal Land Bank, (2 folders)
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Radio Commission
    - Federal Surplus Relief Corps
    - Federal Tariff Commission
    - Federal Trade Commission
    - Fish
    - Flood control
    - Foreign affairs
      - German atrocities
      - St. Lawrence Treaty
      - Miscellaneous
    - Foreign debt
    - Fort Hall, Pocatello, Idaho, replica (Box 381)
    - Freight rates
    - General, (4 folders)
    - Geological survey
    - Gold hoarding
    - Grebe, G. W.
    - Gumberg, Alex
    - Home Loan banks
    - Homeowners Loan Corp.
    - Hungary
    - Immigration
    - Independent school district, (2 folders) (Box 382)
    - Indian legislation
    - Interior Department
    - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - I.O.N. Highway (U.S. 95)
    - Invitations (by state)
      - Alabama-Idaho, (10 folders)
      - Idaho-Massachusetts, (11 folders) (Box 383)
      - Michigan-Oregon, (16 folders) (Box 384)
      - Pennsylvania-Wyoming, (12 folders) (Box 385)
    - International Labor Organization
    - Justice Department
    - Labor
      - Immigration
      - Nationalization
    - Legislation
      - Antilynching bill
      - Bankhead Bill
      - Birth control (Box 386)
      - Bonus
      - Civilian Works Administration, discontinuance of
      - Coconut oil
      - Emergency Farm Mortgage Act
      - Excise tax
      - Frazier-Lemke Bill
      - Incorporation law
      - Interstate Commerce Act
      - Jute tax
      - Manganese
      - Meat packing bill
      - Munitions manufacturers, investigation of (Box 387)
      - Neely Bill
      - Radio, (2 folders)
      - Rayburn Bill
      - Res. 154
      - Salaries
      - Sales tax
      - Tobacco control
      - Tugwell Bill
      - Veterans, (1 folder) (Box 388)
      - Wagner Bill
      - Miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Letters of introduction
    - Letters of introduction, Russia
    - Levinson, Salmon O.
    - Lists (Box 389)
    - Long, Huey
    - McKaig, Ray
    - Manuscripts of speeches and statements of others, (3 folders)
    - Mead, Elwood
    - Mexican Claims Commission
    - Miscellaneous, (1 folder); (6 folders) (Box 390)
    - Miscellaneous, Boise, Idaho
    - National banks (Box 391)
    - National Recovery Administration
      - Darrow, Clarence, report
      - Homeowners loan
      - Lumber code, (3 folders)
      - Moving picture code
      - Oil
      - Small business, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 392)
      - Steel code, (2 folders)
      - Tennessee Valley Voter League
      - Trusts, monopolies, (3 folders) (Box 393)
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 394)
    - Naval race
    - Navy Department
    - Newspapers, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 395)
    - Oil, (2 folders)
    - Oil, Thomas Bill, (2 folders)
    - Oil dictatorship
    - Patents
    - Patronage, appointments (Box 396)
      - Allen, Florence
      - Anderson, C. C.
      - Arney, C. E.
      - Coolidge, T. Jefferson
      - Idaho
      - Nevada judges
      - Welles, Sumner G.
      - Miscellaneous
    - Pardons and paroles
    - Pension legislation, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 397)
    - Personal
      - Presidency
      - Public record
      - Miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Philippine legislation
    - Political (Box 398)
      - Campaign Expenditures Committee
      - Carter, Captain, case
      - Idaho, (2 folders)
      - Personal
      - Republican party
        - Reorganization, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 399)
    - Post Office Department
    - Post Office legislation
    - Production Credit Association
    - Prohibition
    - Public health
    - Public utilities
    - Public Works Administration
    - Public Works Program
    - Radio speeches, 1934
      - July 4
      - Mar. 22
      - 19 Nov.
    - Railroad legislation (Box 400)
    - Reciprocal Tariff
    - Reconstruction Finance Corp.
    - Relief investigation
    - Republican party reorganization
    - Requests for
      - Photographs
      - Speeches, (2 folders)
    - Robins, Raymond (Box 401)
    - Rockwell, Irvin E.
    - Rural rehabilitation
    - Russia
    - Russia, applications for positions
    - Silver, (2 folders)
    - Standards Bureau
    - State Department
    - Subsistence homesteads (Box 402)
    - Sugar agreement
    - Tariff
    - Tariff agreement, president's power to make, (2 folders)
    - Tariff Commission
    - Tax processing
    - Taxation
    - Tennessee Valley project (Box 403)
    - Transients relief
    - Treasury Department
    - Unemployment
    - United States Employees' Compensation
    - Veterans
    - War Department, (2 folders)
    - Washburn, R. M.
    - West Point, N.Y., United States Military Academy, (2 folders)
    - World Court
  - 1935 (Box 404)
    - Agriculture
    - Agricultural Adjustment Act, (2 folders)
    - Agricultural Adjustment Administration
      - Apples
      - Potatoes, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 405)
    - American Crusaders, Inc.
    - Annapolis, Md., United States Naval Academy
    - Application for loan
    - Applications for positions
      - A-J, (9 folders)
      - K-Y, (13 folders) (Box 406)
    - Appointments
    - Appropriations
    - Articles, (1 folder) (Box 407)
    - Bank legislation
    - Banks, central
    - Bird sanctuary
    - Black Canyon Irrigation District, Idaho
    - Borah, William Edgar, personal
    - Cache National Forest
    - Census Bureau
    - Charity
    - Civil Service Commission
    - Civilian Conservation Corps
    - Claims, (2 folders) (Box 408)
    - Coal legislation
    - Columbia Valley Authority
    - Comments on speeches, (3 folders)
    - Commissioner of Reclamation
    - Committee on Foreign Relations
    - Condolences (Box 409)
    - Congratulations
    - Congressional Library
    - Congressional Record
    - Currency and money question
    - Documents, (4 folders)
    - Economy Act
    - Education Office
    - Emergency Relief Appropriation Act
    - Escheat law
    - Fair trade contract
    - Farm Credit Administration (Box 410)
    - Federal Alcohol bill
    - Federal buildings
    - Federal Communications Commission
    - Federal Deposit Insurance Corp.
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration, (2 folders)
    - Federal Employees' Compensation Commission, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 411)
    - Federal Farm Board
    - Federal Housing Administration
    - Federal Land bank, (2 folders)
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Tariff Commission
    - Fisheries, Bureau of
    - Flood control
    - Foreign affairs
      - Copyright treaty, (2 folders)
      - Germany (Box 412)
      - Neutrality
      - Reciprocity with Canada
      - S.J. Resolution 103
      - St. Lawrence Seaway Treaty
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Forest Reserves
    - Forest Service, (2 folders)
    - Fort Hall, Idaho, replica
    - Gannett, Frank E.
    - General, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 413)
    - General Land Office, (2 folders)
    - Gold
    - Gumberg, Alex
    - Holt, Rush D.
    - Homeowners Loan Corp., (3 folders)
    - Immigration Bureau
    - Immigration matters
    - Independent School District, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 414)
    - Indian affairs
    - Interior Department
    - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Invitations (by state)
      - California-Indiana, (10 folders)
      - Illinois-New York City, (17 folders) (Box 415)
      - New York City-West Virginia, (16 folders) (Box 416)
      - Wisconsin-Wyoming, (2 folders) (Box 417)
    - King Hill Irrigation District
    - Labor, protest regarding day labor
    - Legislation
      - Adjusted Service Certificates, (3 folders)
      - Agricultural Adjustment Act
      - Antilynching
      - Bankhead Bill
      - Birth control
      - Campaign expenditures
      - Federal election expense
      - Frazier-Lemke Bill, (2 folders) (Box 418)
      - Income tax
      - Inheritance tax
      - Interstate Commerce, (2 folders)
      - Life insurance investigation
      - Long and short haul
      - Manganese
      - Monopoly licensing bill
      - Patent pool (Box 419)
      - Price-fixing
      - Pure Food and Drug bill
      - Rayburn Bill, (4 folders)
      - Salaries
      - Securities Act
      - Special attention
      - Tax bill of 1935
      - Thirty-hour week bill, (2 folders)
      - Underwriting agents, bonds
      - Wagner Bill (Box 420)
      - Wilcox Bill, Air Defense Program
      - Miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Letters of introduction, (2 folders)
    - Levinson, Salmon O.
    - Lists
    - Lobby investigation
    - Long, Huey P., investigation of assassination of
    - McKaig, Ray
    - Manuscripts submitted to Borah, (4 folders) (Box 421)
    - Mexico investigation, (3 folders) (Box 422)
    - Mines and mining, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 423)
    - Monopoly, (2 folders)
    - National Emergency Council
    - National Park Service
    - National Recovery Administration (Box 424)
      - Homeowners Loan Commissioner
      - Monopoly investigation, (3 folders)
      - Monopoly, price fixing
      - Small business
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 425)
    - National Youth Administration, (2 folders)
    - Naturalization Bureau
    - Naval
    - Navy Department
    - Newspapers, (4 folders)
    - Oil (Box 426)
    - Paroles and pardons
    - Patents
    - Patronage, appointments
      - Anderson, C. C.
      - Arney, C. E.
      - Miscellaneous
    - Pension legislation, (4 folders) (Box 427)
    - Personal
      - Presidency, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 428)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 429)
    - Political
      - Campaign expenditures
      - Cutting, Bronson, M., investigation
      - Idaho, (2 folders)
      - Personal, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 430)
      - Reorganization of Republican party
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Post Office Department
    - Postal
    - Prohibition and liquor question
    - Public Health Service
    - Public Roads Bureau
    - Public utilities (Box 431)
    - Public works program
    - Quinn plan
    - Railroad legislation
    - Railroad Retirement Board
    - Reclamation, (2 folders)
    - Reconstruction Finance Corp.
    - Relief
      - Administration of
      - Investigation
      - McCarran Amendment, (2 folders) (Box 432)
    - Requests for
      - Photographs
      - Speeches
    - Resettlement Administration
    - Robins, Raymond
    - Rockwell, Irvin E.
    - Rural and Alaska rehabilitation
    - Russia, (2 folders)
    - Schreiner, George A.
    - Securities and Exchange Commission
    - Silver
    - Social
    - Speeches
    - Standards Bureau (Box 433)
    - State Department, (2 folders)
    - Sugar
    - Suing the government
    - Surveys
    - Tariff
      - Canadian treaty
      - Legislation, pulp wood
      - Matches
    - Taxes
      - Luxury tax on furs
      - Processing
    - Taxation
    - Tennessee Valley Project (Box 434)
    - Treasury Department
    - Verde River irrigation
    - Veterans Administration
    - War Department, (2 folders)
    - Washburn, R. M.
    - West Point, N.Y., United States Military Academy, (2 folders)
    - Works Progress Administration
    - World Court
  - 1936 (Box 435)
    - Agriculture
      - General
      - Adjustment Administration
      - Department of
      - Noxious weeds
      - Situation
    - Annapolis, Md., United States Naval Academy, (2 folders)
    - Appointments with Borah, (2 folders)
    - Appropriations (Box 436)
    - Articles
      - Granted
      - Redbook Magazine
      - Requested
    - Bank legislation
    - Bible, Howard W.
    - Biological survey
    - Blister rust control
    - Bonus
    - Borah, William Edgar, public record
    - Business
      - Clithero note
      - Income tax
      - Lodge dues
      - Taxes
      - Miscellaneous
    - Cache National Forest
    - Census Bureau
    - Chamber of Commerce
    - Charity
    - Child labor
    - Civil Service Commission, (2 folders) (Box 437)
    - Claims
    - Comments on speeches, (2 folders)
    - Commerce Department
    - Committee on Foreign Relations
    - Community Sanitation Project
    - Condolences
    - Congratulations
    - Congressional Library lists
    - Congressional Record (Box 438)
    - Crank mail
    - Currency and money questions
    - Dilworth, Melborne E.
    - Documents, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 439)
    - Education Office
    - Employees' Compensation Commission
    - Entomology Bureau
    - Farm Credit Administration
    - Federal buildings
    - Federal Coordinator of transportation
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration
    - Federal Land banks, (2 folders)
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Reserve banks
    - Federal Tariff Commission
    - Federal Trade Commission
    - Federal Writers project
    - Flood control
    - Football tickets
    - Foreign affairs
      - Neutrality and war situation
      - Panama Canal Treaty
      - Miscellaneous (Box 440)
    - Forest Service, (2 folders)
    - Fort Hall, Idaho, replica
    - Gannett, Frank E.
    - General, (2 folders)
    - General Land Office
    - Geological Survey (Box 441)
    - Government Printing Office
    - Home Owners Loan Corp.
    - Immigration Bureau
    - Indian Affairs Bureau
    - Interior Department
    - Internal Revenue Bureau
    - International Joint Commission
    - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Introductions and recommendations, (2 folders)
    - Invitations (by state)
      - California-Florida, (5 folders)
      - Idaho-New Jersey, (19 folders) (Box 442)
      - New York-Wisconsin, (18 folders) (Box 443)
    - Judiciary Committee
    - Justice Department
    - Knox, Frank
    - Labor Department (Box 444)
    - Labor matters
    - Legislation
      - Antilynching bill
      - Bankhead Cotton Control Bill
      - Birth control
      - Bonus
      - Borah Bill (S. 3772)
      - Commodity Exchange bill, (2 folders)
      - Copeland Pure Food and Drug Act
      - Copper Marketing bill
      - Copyright bill
      - Culkin Motoin Picture bill
      - Educational
      - Federal Land Bank loans
      - Federal Theatre Project
      - Frazier-Lemke Bill
      - Guffey Coal Bill (Box 445)
      - H.R. 4688
      - H.R. 8180
      - Immunity of members in D.C.
      - Interstate Commerce Act, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - National Housing Act
      - Philippine travel pay
      - Processing taxes, return of
      - Recreation fund, army (Box 446)
      - Reduction interest rate of HOLC mortgages
      - S. 3670
      - Small business
      - Small Lobby Bill
      - Social Security bill
      - Vocational education
      - Wheeler Bill
    - Levinson, Salmon O.
    - Library books
    - Lists
    - Loans to fruitmen
    - McKaig, Ray
    - Manuscripts, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 447)
    - Marine Corps
    - Merchant Marine
    - Mexico
    - Mines, Bureau of
    - Minidoka National Forest
    - Miscellaneous, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 448)
    - Monopoly
    - National Emergency Council
    - National Park Service
    - Naturalization Bureau
    - Navy Department
    - Newspapers, (3 folders)
    - Office copy
    - Oil
    - Pardon, paroles
    - Patents, Bureau of
    - Patronage, appointments
      - Arney, C. E.
      - Miscellaneous
    - Pension legislation (Box 449)
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Townsend Plan, (4 folders)
    - Personal
      - Borah, William Edgar
      - Johnson, Claudius O.
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 450)
      - Presidency
        - Campaign expenditures
        - Confidential, (3 folders)
    - Pipe lines
    - Political
      - Campaign expenditures
      - Miscellaneous, (1 folder)
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 451)
      - Personal, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 452, Box 453)
      - Presidency
      - Primary campaign expense
      - Primary, congratulations
      - Republican platform
    - Political science
    - Post Office Department
    - Post Office legislation
    - Positions, request for
      - A-D
      - E-W, (4 folders) (Box 454)
    - Potatoes
    - Presidency
      - Coughlin, Charles E., matter
      - Landon, Alfred M., (2 folders)
      - Wanamaker Treaty (Box 455)
    - Public Health, Bureau of
    - Public Roads
    - Public Works Administration
    - Radio station, Federal Communications Commission
    - Railroad legislation
    - Railroad Retirement Board
    - Reclamation, Bureau of, (2 folders)
    - Relief investigation
    - Requests for
      - Photographs, (1 folder) (Box 456)
      - Speeches, (3 folders)
    - Resettlement Administration and farm
      - debt adjustment
    - Robinson-Patman Bill
    - Rockwell, Irvin E.
    - Rural Alaska Rehabilitation
    - Rural electrification
    - Russia
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, Washington, D.C.
    - Salmon National Forest
    - Schreiner, George A.
    - Securities Exchange Commission
    - Silver (Box 457)
    - Social security
    - Soil conservation
    - Speech, Washington and the Constitution
    - Star route
    - State Department, (2 folders)
    - Sugar
    - Suspension mining claims
    - Tariff legislation, (2 folders)
    - Tax bill, Russell amendment (Box 458)
    - Taxation
      - Excise tax on fats and oils
      - General
    - Tennessee Valley Authority
    - Treasury Department
    - Unemployment
    - United States Employees' Compensation Commission
    - Veterans Administration
    - War Department
    - Washburn, R. M.
    - Watercarriers bill
    - West Point, N.Y., United States Military Academy, (2 folders)
    - Works Progress Administration, (2 folders) (Box 459)
  - 1937
    - Agriculture, general
    - Agriculture
      - Apples
      - Beans
      - Compulsory control, (2 folders)
      - Drought rates
      - Miscellaneous
      - Potatoes (Box 460)
      - Resettlement Administration
      - Sugar
      - Wheat
      - Wool
    - American Falls Units, American Falls, Idaho, (2 folders)
    - "American Farmer" articles (Box 461)
    - Annapolis, Md., United States Naval Academy
    - Annapolis, Md., United States Naval Academy, appointees
    - Applications for positions, (4 folders)
    - Appointments
    - Appropriations, (2 folders) (Box 462)
    - Army matters
    - Articles, granted
    - Bank legislation
    - Big lost River Irrigation District
    - Biological survey
    - Black Canyon Irrigation District, Idaho
    - Black, Hugo LaFayette, appointment to Supreme Court
    - Blister rust
    - Borah, William Edgar
      - Personal
      - Redbook article
    - Bureau of Fisheries
    - Bureau of Mines, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 463)
    - Bureau of Reclamation, (3 folders)
    - Cache National Forest
    - Charity
    - Civil Service Commission (Box 464)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps
    - Claims
    - Committee, Judiciary
    - Comments on speeches
    - Commerce Department
    - Condolences
    - Congratulations
    - Congressional intelligence
    - Congressional Library lists
    - Congressional Record
    - Constitutional government speech, (2 folders) (Box 465)
    - Currency, monetary matters
    - Dairy problem
    - Depletion of mines
    - Documents, (4 folders)
    - Farm credit (Box 466)
    - Farm speech
    - Fascism speech, (3 folders)
    - Federal buildings
    - Federal Communications Commission
    - Federal Farm Loan Act
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration
    - Federal Housing Administration (Box 467)
    - Federal Land Bank
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Trade Commission
    - Flood control
    - Foreign affairs
      - General
      - Argentine Sanitary Treaty, (3 folders)
      - Foreign affairs
      - Debt payments (Box 468)
      - Jews
      - Miscellaneous
      - Neutrality legislation
      - Palestine
      - Puerto Rico
      - Reciprocal trade agreements
      - St. Lawrence Waterway
    - Foreign letters
    - Forest Reserve
    - Forest Service
    - Fort Hall, Idaho (Box 469)
      - Irrigation Projection
      - Replica
    - General, (2 folders)
    - General Land Office
    - Government Printing Office
    - Green River and Bear Lake
    - Homeowners Loan Corp.
    - Idaho Cooperation Loan Corp.
    - Immigration
    - Impeachment of Judge Geiger (Box 470)
    - Indian affairs
    - Interior Department
    - Internal Revenue
    - International Joint Commission
    - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Invitations (by state)
      - Arkansas-Montana, (17 folders)
      - Nebraska-Wyoming, (20 folders) (Box 471)
    - Justice Department
    - Labor Department
    - Labor, north Idaho
    - Legislation (Box 472)
      - Antilynching
      - Bankruptcy matters
      - Black-Connery Bill, (2 folders)
      - Black, Hugo LaFayette
      - Borah Licensing Bill
      - Car limit
      - Child labor, (2 folders)
      - Civilian Conservation Corps
      - Community property
      - Connally Oil Bill (Box 473)
      - Copyright Act
      - Delegation of power
      - Education, (2 folders)
      - Equal Rights Amendment
      - Federal Communications Commission,. investigation
      - Federal Home Loan Board bill
      - Firearms
      - Frazier-Lemke Bill
      - S.J.R. 160, relating to fur bearinganimals
      - General Welfare Act
      - Government departments
      - Guffey Coal Bill
      - Harrison Resolution
      - Healey Divorce Bill
      - H.J.Res. 389 (Box 474)
      - H.R. 4721
      - Interstate Commerce Commission
      - Jute
      - Labor Relations Board
      - Legalization of National Recovery Act codes
      - McCarran Bill
      - Mining laws, repeal of
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - National House Act
      - O'Mahoney Bill
      - Patent laws
      - Percentage depletion (Box 475)
      - Pettengill Bill
      - Phosphate Commission
      - Phosphate investigation
      - Pipelines
      - Post Office
      - Price-fixing by law
      - Regional Planning bill